Guide to the Department of Fine Arts records, 1922-1959.
Department of Fine Arts records, 1922-1959.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Department of Fine Arts records, 1922-1959.
14-14-818
Cornell University. Dept. of Fine Arts.
3.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, minutes, accounts, inventories, archaeological notes, programs, and printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, minutes, accounts, inventories, archaeological notes, programs, and printed material; department chairman was Frederick O. Waage. Organizations represented include the American Numismatic Society, the Archaeological Institute of America, and the College Art Association of America. Major correspondents include Cornelius William De Kiewiet, and Deane W. Malott.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, minutes, accounts, inventories, archaeological notes, programs, and printed material; department chairman was Frederick O. Waage. Organizations represented include the American Numismatic Society, the Archaeological Institute of America, and the College Art Association of America. Major correspondents include Cornelius William De Kiewiet, and Deane W. Malott.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Dept. of Fine Arts.; De Kiewiet, C. W. (Cornelius William), 1902-; Malott, Deane W. (Deane Waldo), 1898-; Waage, Frederick Oswin, 1906-1985; American Numismatic Society.; Archaeological Institute of America.; College Art Association of America.
Subjects:
Art history--Study and teaching.; Archaeology--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Assorted correspondences, ca. 1935-1953 (Box 1)
  Organizations:
  Arizona Anthropological Association
  Art Institute of Chicago
  American Numismatic Society
  American Association of Museums
  American School of Classical Studies at Athens, Greece
  Art Trading Company
  Archeological Institute of America
  Committee for the Excavation of Antioch and its Vicinity
  Oriental Institute
  Correspondents include:
  Vicky Athanassiou
  Richard Aldrich, Wesleyan College
  Robert J. Braidwood, Oriental Institute, University of Chicago
- Assorted correspondences; accounts; minutes, ca. 1935-1953 (Box 2)
  College Art Association
  Robert Caldwell
  Rhys Carpenter
  Howard Comfort
  N.C. Debevoise
  C.W. deKiewiet
- Assorted correspondences; notes re: publication of Antioch IV; department purchases of coins and casts, ca. 1937-1956 (Box 3)
  Ethnographic Board (National Research Council)
  George Banta Publishing Company
  Hetty Goldman
  Various of Cornell faculty and administration
- Assorted correspondences, ca. 1936-1956 (Box 4)
  DeWitt Historical Society
  Princeton University
  Rufus Morey, Princeton University
- Assorted correspondences, ca. 1935-1956 (Box 5)
  Cornell University
  Dean R.M. Ogden, Cornell University
  Dean Paul M. O'Leary, Cornell University
  Ruth L. Schurman, editorial assistant of the Oriental Institute
  Hans Henning von der Osten, Oriental Institute
  Doris Fessler, Oriental Institute
- Assorted correspondences; notes on publication of Antioch IV; list of Antioch notebooks sent to R. Stillwell at Princeton, ca. 1933-1956 (Box 6)
  Johns Hopkins University
  Raymond & Raymond Galleries, New York
  G.M.A. Richter re: publication of Antioch lamps
  D.M. Robinson, Johns Hopkins University
  Richard Stillwell, Princeton University
  Baldwin E. Smith, Princeton University
- Assorted correspondences, ca. 1935-1955 (Box 7)
  Harvard University
  Strategic Services Office
  Catherine Udall, Harvard University
  R.F.S. Starr, Princeton University
  Paul Underwood
  Homer Thompson
  R.S. Young
- Accounts and receipts: Fine Arts Department, 1956-1959 (Box 8)
- Accounts and receipts: Archaeology Department, 1940-1948 (Box 8)
- Accounts and receipts: Archaeology Department, 1948-1959 (Box 9)
- Accounts and receipts: Fine Arts Department, 1940-1956 (Box 10)
- Research grant, 1939-1940 (Box 10)
- Requisition note pad (Box 10)
- Payroll folder, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
- Accounts, 1931-1947 (Box 11)
  Fine Arts
  Archaeology
  Archaeological Appropriation
  Museum maintenance
- Archaeology study/research notes on monument inscriptions from Attica, Greece. (Box 12)
  Most have corresponding C.I.A. ( Corpus Inscriptionum Atticarum) references. Also notes on progression of Old Attic letter forms (pre-403 B.C.).